Yuniel Acosta

Software Engineer

Address Ciego de Avila, Ciego de Avila, 65100 LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/yacosta738/ Phone

+53 54739922 yunielacosta738@gmail.com GitHub

https://www.github.com/yacosta738

Bilingual Software Architect with a background in various software programs and languages. A talented performer with over 3 years of conducting software architecture reviews and reporting on the results and familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements like Java/Kotlin/Scala with Spring Boot framework and HTML, CSS, JavaScript/Typescript with Vueis and Angular Frameworks. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities.



E-mail

Skills

API design knowledge

Software automation

Agile

Java proficiency

JavaScript programming

Algorithm implementation





Work Experience

Aug 2020 -Present

Software Architect

Desoft, Ciego de Avila, Ciego de Avila

- Authored development guidelines to expedite application design efforts through ready-made frameworks.
- Created migration strategies to bridge development gaps between existing software architecture and future updates.
- Developed application architecture strategy to specifically align with employer business goals.
- Communicated software architecture strategies to senior leadership and third-party business leaders.

Jan 2018 -Aug 2020

FullStack Developer

Desoft, Ciego de Avila, Ciego de Avila

- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for project plans.
- Boosted network, system and data availability and integrity through preventive maintenance and upgrades.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Adjusted design parameters to boost performance and incorporate new features.

Sept 2017 -Dec 2017

Web Developer Intern

Desoft, Ciego de Avila, Ciego de Avila

- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for project plans.
- Boosted network, system and data availability and integrity through preventive maintenance and upgrades.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Adjusted design parameters to boost performance and incorporate new features.



Education

Jul 2017

Sept 2012 - Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

Central University "Marta Abreu" of Las Villas Santa Clara, Villa Clara, Cuba

• Thesis: Manipulación de series de datos espacio-temporales mediante el uso de formatos de datos científicos y geográficos en R



Languages

English Spanish

